Junior Full-Stack Developer

KRISZTIAN KESERU

Phone: 07453306232

Email: krisztian.keseru@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/krisztian-keseru-a09804ba

Address: 110 Savick Way, Lea, Preston, PR2 1XA

Full UK Driving Licence

PERSONAL PROFILE:

An enthusiastic professional individual who is seeking a new challenging career after 9 years of being in Warehousing in the UK. I am a diligent individual who strives to achieve the best in all areas, and I am always eager to learn new skills and advance my career. As this is a huge career change, I have completed the Full-Stack Software Development course at Code Institute, and I am keen to build upon my knowledge and continue to learn within this sector. After my years spent as a System Administrator in the past, I decided to change sides and become a Software Developer. As a Full Stack Developer, I like to work on application logic and querying databases using Python and PHP Back-End languages. I think my problem-solving experience on the hardware side will be useful as a developer. As a self-motivated individual, I am keen to follow my dream within this new industry of becoming a Junior Developer or Junior Back-end Developer.

CORE PROGRAMMING SKILLS:

Front-End

➤ HTML 5

CSS3, SASS

JavaScript, jQuery

Back-End

- Python (flask, django)
- > PHP (Laravel)
- MySQL, MongoDB

Frameworks, Source Control

- Bootstrap
- ➢ Git
- ➢ Github

PROJECTS:

My main self created projects during the Full-Stack Software Development course.

1st Milestone Project – User Centric Frontend Development

Z Services is a small business who cleaning windows with purified water in Wigan and surrounding areas. HTML, pure CSS only. No frameworks used at this project. github.com/milka77/z-services

2nd Milestone Project – Interactive Frontend Development

FIA WEC (World Endurance Championship) themed interactive JavaScript memory game. HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap. github.com/milka77/ms2_memorygame

3rd Milestone Project – Data Centric Development

Online Cook book, users can add, upgrade and delete recipes to the database. Python(flask), MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Font Awesome and Bootstrap. github.com/milka77/ms3_cookbook

4th Milestone Project – Full-Stack Frameworks with Django

SimDriver School is an e-commerce shop selling digital content which is providing help to sim racers with weekly setups and videos to improve their lap times and consistency with the sim title iRacing.com.

Python(Django), Jinja, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Font Awesome and Bootstrap.

github.com/milka77/ci-ms4-simdriver-school

EDUCATION:

2019-2020 – DipHE (EQF Level 5) Diploma in Software Development at Code Institute Grade: Second Class Honours
(HTML5, CSS3 (Bootstrap), JavaScript, Python, MySQL, MongoDB)

2010-2011 - Diploma of Software Operator of Computer Technology and Web-designer (HTML)

2001-2002 – Diploma of Programmer and Software-Operator (MS Office)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

2012-Present: Waitrose, Warehouse Assistant (John Lewis Partnership), Leyland, UK

Duties:

- General warehouse duties (goods in, picking, FLT etc.)
- Delivering high standards with an average performance of 108% yearly.
- Member of the C.I. Team(Continuous Improvement)
- C.I. Projects (e.g. taking apart of warehouse layout planning and relaying, finding solutions for daily work routines, making work processes more effective and quicker)
- Training new staff on processes.

2003-2012: TH Informatics (IT Sales and Support), Pecs, Hungary

IT Professional in a computer shop served over 15000 customers for 9 years – excellent customer service and communication skills for professionals and laymen, on phone and in person as well.

Duties:

- Designed and maintained the company's website
- Built, serviced and upgraded computers
- Controlled stock for orders and walk-in customers
- Built communication skills by speaking with customers in person, over the phone and via email on a
 daily basis dealt with enquiries and found solutions for complaints

1999 – 2003: 5090 Interspar (IT System Administrator), Pecs, Hungary

Accomplished the daily tasks of an IT System administrator, contributing to special projects as a system admin such as supervising a structured network of the Hypermarket.

Provided desktop, PC supply and hardware support for over 70 PCs and 5 laptops, responding professionally to enquiries and providing support within target time frames.

Duties:

- Verified that peripherals were working properly
- Maintained IT systems (70 Workstations, 20 printers, 5 servers, 35 cash registers)
- Quickly identified the source of failure and arrange the repair for hardware on the occasion of failure
- Monitored system performance
- User administration (set up and maintained user accounts)
- Prepared the system for hardware or software updates by deadlines.

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES:

- I'm an enthusiastic sim-racer, enjoying the competition to race with other drivers. Just like at the race I never give up, be fair and trying to accomplish everything that I started at work or in my life.
- My other and maybe the biggest love is IT. New gadgets, new useful technology for every aspect of life. I try and keep up with all the news and update my knowledge. I was used HTML and CSS in the past and always want to create dynamic websites and learn the PHP language, so after I finished my study at Code Institute and received my diploma I decided to get a few courses on Udemy.com and learn PHP programming.
- To broaden my knowledge with frameworks started a study of Laravel and React.
- I like to have a relaxed weekend with friends and get recharged my energy for the next week which is fantastic.

PERSONAL PROJECTS:

After finished the basic PHP courses (PHP basics, MySQL, PDO etc.) started building a "Home Application" that should make our family's day to day life easier. The app contains 3 main sections like Meter readings, Vegan food recipes and shopping list, exercise tracking all these have CRUD functions. Meanwhile, I finished PHP Object Oriented Programming, MVC Frameworks and Laravel courses at Udemy.com. Now I'm updating the "Home Application" with the MVC framework and starting my journey with Laravel refactoring my 3rd project the online cook book with Laravel framework. Preparing the next step of my Full-Stack Development career, which will be the React JS front-end framework.